<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toastmasters on Vincent Filby&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/tags/toastmasters/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Toastmasters on Vincent Filby&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/10.0.1.40:1313/tags/toastmasters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sell Your Skills - Toastmasters Table Topics</title>
      <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/sell-your-skills-toastmasters-table-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 02:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/sell-your-skills-toastmasters-table-topics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Table_topic&#34; title=&#34;Link:
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Table_topic&#34;&gt;Table Topics&lt;/a&gt; theme (impromptu one minute
speeches) at a recent meeting and it went over really well. The idea is that
each volunteer is pretending to have a skill set and they are trying to sell
that skill set for a completely unrelated job. Some examples that I used
were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are a gourmet chef interviewing for a pet food tasting position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are a cowboy interviewing for a make-up consultant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have some latitude to work with this theme, you can make it more serious
or more playful depending on the meeting. You can download the full script
and topics .pdf below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https
://phaven-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/files/document_part/asset/935606
/vg5hA0wkbC07g-a59BhVhmSjQqM/Toastmasters_-
_2013_05_27_Sell_your_skills_table_topics.pdf&#34;&gt;Download Toastmasters_-_2013_05_27_Sell_your_skills_table_topics.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Thousand Words</title>
      <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/one-thousand-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/one-thousand-words/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My second Toastmasters speech for the project &amp;ldquo;Organize Your Speech.&amp;rdquo; This
is written for speaking, not for reading so take it as such. There is also
an accompanying slideshow of images, if you are interested in seeing the full
presentation contact me on twitter @vfilby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a moment and try to remember a photograph that has made a lasting
impression on you. (3s pause)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now ask yourself why, why did it make a lasting impression. Chances are good
that you felt an emotional connection, that the photo atold a storya to
you. I have seen and forgotten thousands of very pretty pictures, but the
photos that tell me a story have always stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Toastmaster, fellow toastmasters, and honored guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a photographer, the most powerful thing you can do is to create a
photograph that tells a story. Today I would like to share three lessons
that I have learned to help tell a story with a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1 Get Real&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The famed street photographer Henri Cartier-Bresson said that everything has a
decisive moment. And if you miss that moment it is gone forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decisive moment is the moment that tells the story.  That moment lives
in the real world&amp;hellip; it does not live in the studio and it most certainly does
not pose in pictures for a slice of fine cheddar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it real I avoid posed photos and I shoot candidly. When you ask
someone to pose for a photo 9 times out of 10 you will get that fake,
perfunctory smile that I would normally expect from an airline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you catch them unaware of the camera you will see the real expression and
that moment unfolding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is lesson #1: Focus on the moment and shoot candidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now unless the story your are trying to capture, is asomeone yelling at
youa I wouldnat walk up to a stranger and try this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting real is not enough. You need to get to know a person before you can
begin to tell their story. and that brings us to &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2 Get Engaged&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genuine expression and emotion is the cornerstone of a great photo. The only
way to get genuine is to build a relationship with the person&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engage people and strive to understand them. Only once you build a
relationship with a person will they let their guard down and let the genuine
shine through. This takes a lot more time that stealthy snapping photos from
the shadows but it is more rewarding. And you wonat have angry people
chasing you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same idea applies to places as well. I need to explore a place before I
can understand it. Often my favourite photos are taken from hidden nooks and
crannies, from well off the beaten path, or from places where tourists donat
go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engaging places and people is essential to understanding them. And
Understanding them is essential to telling their story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is lesson #2. Getting Real and getting engaged are incredibly
important, but I am going to entreat you to go what step further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3 Get Your Hands Dirty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have laid in the mud &amp;hellip; withstood the bitter cold &amp;hellip; and even tested my
wifeas patience making her wait while I took pictures of a astupida
tree. I have learned: never be afraid to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I take pictures as a bystander&amp;hellip; the photos feel like they are a
bystander. But when I am in the middle of the action&amp;hellip; the photos feel like
they are in the middle of the action.  Getting involved will help you tell
the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, never be afraid to get closer.  Getting closer shows so
much more detail! Detail is candy for the imagination, and detail will help
your story unfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letas do an experiment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the three lessons I have learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get real by avoiding posed photos and focussing on the moment as it unfolds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get engaged: by talking to people, trying to understand them, and by exploring places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get my hands dirty by getting up close and getting in the middle of the action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you practice assiduously, anyone can take photographs that tell a story and
live up to the old adage that a picture is worth 1000 words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Roots</title>
      <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/rural-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/rural-roots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a verbatim copy of my first Toastmasters speech&amp;hellip; the ice breaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in rural ontario. My address was Lot 17, Concession B, Camden
Township. The nearest town, Thamesville, had a population of 900 people&amp;hellip; and
they were very proud of their traffic light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to see a movie you had to drive half an hour. If you wanted to
see a &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; movie you had to drive an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gossip section in the local &lt;em&gt;weekly&lt;/em&gt; paper was an &lt;em&gt;accurate&lt;/em&gt; record of who
visited whom during the week&amp;hellip; and for what purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mme Toastmaster, fellow toastmasters, (and honored guests). Thamesville was
not as isolated as Timmins or Moosonee, but it is pretty far from city life.
I would like to share some of the ways that growing up rural influenced me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson #1: Local Food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite living in the country my family were not farmers; However, we had a
small piece of land that we used for land for pastures, orchards and crops.
Every year we grew enough corn for ourselves and to sell locally. And I can
assure with 100% certainty that this is made me a Seasonal Produce Aficionado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have only every purchased corn from a grocery store you might not know
what corn actually tastes like. You see the moment corn is picked it starts
converting sugar to starch, and by the time it gets to the grocery store it
has already lost a large part of itas goodness. Corn picked fresh should
be so sweet and crunchy that you can eat it raw without cooking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving home the corn that I found in local grocery stores was a poor
imitation of what I was used to, so I stopped eating it altogether. And I
continued avoiding corn until I found a local farmer that sold fresh picked
corn. And difference was astounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now whenever I move to a new city finding a good source for local produce is
an essential task. I would encourage anyone to buy local produce, generally
the produce is fresher and you are supporting local farmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson #2: Step out of the comfort zone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we may had some excellent seasonal ingredients, exotic cuisine was never
Thamesvilleas fort&amp;copy;. We had two ethnic restaurants: Chinese and Pizza.
Everything else was sensible and consistent: meat, potatoes and vegetables.
Nothing crazy, and well within the comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a number of years later. I found myself in South Korea being
served a traditional Korean dinner where the majority of the courses were
strange seafoody things. Nothing sensible like meat and potatoes, and well
outside the comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked hesitantly at the array in front of me&amp;hellip; my gaze shifting from dish
to dish to the Korean host and back to the dishes. And I thought to myself,
when else will I have the opportunity to try traditional Korean food in
Korea. And who knows, I might even like them! So I tried each dish. I was
pleasantly surprised to discover that at least one of the courses&amp;hellip; was
bearable. The others, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard for me to leave my comfort zone. I may not have like the
traditional Korean dishes, but without pushing the boundaries I wouldnat
have discovered how much I like other ethnic foods. To reinforce the point
about sensibility and comfort zone, I am proud of my mother for trying Indian
and Thai food for the first time this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson #3: Animals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of my mother, she has always had a soft-spot for animals. Growing up
I watched her take in sick animals whenever they came to our door. It was a
common routine: find a litter of sick and starving kittens, nurse them to
health and adopt them out to good homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She even found notoriety in the local paper when she was trying to free a
skunk who had got is head stuck in a glass jam jar on the side of the road.
The next weekas paper with a front page photo. I canat remember the
title specifically, but I like to tease her that it read aCrazy Lady Frees
Skunk.a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was a little older and it was my responsibility to tend our small herd
of cattle. I recall noticing a calf with an injured foot. Bandaging the foot
of a 300-400 pound calf was not small feat. But each day, I dressed the
calfas wound until it recovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely have my motheras soft spot for animals, I couldnat imagine
not helping an animal in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very thankful for the experiences that I had growing up. Learning about
real food, hands-on experience with farm animals and many other things. Even
though I have since moved to a bigger city and pushed the boundaries of my
comfort zone&amp;hellip; the foundation for my growth comes from my rural roots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>