<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inca Trail on Vincent Filby&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/tags/inca-trail/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inca Trail on Vincent Filby&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/10.0.1.40:1313/tags/inca-trail/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim&#39;s Top Tips</title>
      <link>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/jims-top-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10.0.1.40:1313/post/jims-top-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jim was in our group for the Inca Trail and he has an amusing way off relating
our experiences on his &lt;a href=&#34;http://mylifeoftravel.com/Jimmy.home&#34;&gt;travel blog&lt;/a&gt;.
I encourage you to read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mylifeoftravel.com/ViewJournal.aspx?id=446c3567-1484-43f4-aef2-88b1ddb10284&amp;amp;eid
=b45cefbb-15f9-47cf-8e74-3c2ba282bc1d&#34;&gt;Inca Trail
Entry&lt;/a&gt;, here are some selected quotes for your
enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim on porters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had heard that hiring a porter to carry some of your stuff could be the
difference between enjoying the trail and, well, not. Peru Treks, like most
Inca Trail companies, offer &amp;lsquo;one third of a porter&amp;rsquo; to carry up to 6kg.
Between Katie and I we hoped our two thirds would be the legs and torso. At
least that way he could be roped to another porter and avoid falling off the
mountainside. As it was I believe our porter came as &amp;lsquo;one whole man&amp;rsquo; and
someone elses bag made up the final third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JIM&amp;rsquo;S TOP TIP #68 - hire yourself a small Quechua man (they only come in
&amp;lsquo;small&amp;rsquo;) as a porter - going down to the shops, moving furniture about the
house, taking down gazebos after a garden party&amp;hellip;They are as strong as a
dozen donkeys and have the stamina of an Ethiopian marathon runner. Even the
seventy year olds are probably stronger and fitter than you or I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim on toilets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slip, one wobbly leg, one false step and you shall never return from
&amp;lsquo;The Bog of Eternal Stench&amp;rsquo;. &amp;hellip; the toilets are an environmental hazard
treated with far more respect and caution by our group than, I imagine, all
the high-altitude mountainsides in the Andes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim on Quinoa:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vince, from Canada (not relevant to the story), gesticulating an important
point as the first bowl of quinoa soup was brought to his end of the table.
The scene unfolded in slow motion before my eyes &amp;hellip; his hand connected with
the bowl, which performed a triple somersault with inverted double pike twist,
spraying quinoa all over him, poor Jimmy serving the soup and the roof of the
tent. The bowl landed back on the table, upright, with a mouthful of soup
still in it (thank you centrifugal force), before finding it&amp;rsquo;s way onto the
floor. Well I lost it. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help it. In comedy moments it doesn&amp;rsquo;t
translate well to paper, but to witness it was more than I could handle for 15
minutes. Poor Vince as well. In addition to wearing his dinner he earned the
nickname &amp;lsquo;Quinoa Boy&amp;rsquo;. If there is a saving grace it is that it happened on
the last night and not the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>